Guide to the Monroe Wheeler Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Museum of Modern Art Records (MOMA), 1929-88; Series IX; 22.89; (56 boxes)
  - MOMA EXHIBITION MATERIAL
    - Turner, J. M. W.: Turner, Imagination and Reality (1966)
      - "Turner: Painter of Air, Fire, and Water", article, draft pages, holograph and typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 212, Folder 2601-2602)
      - "Turner: Painter of Air, Fire, and Water", article, drafts, typescript carbon, corrected (Box 212, Folder 2603)
      - "Turner: Painter of Air, Fire, and Water", article, printed version, Look, 1966 Apr 5
      - Clippings, 1965-66 (Box 212, Folder 2604-2605)
    - "20th Anniversary Shows"
      - Office file, 1948-56 (Box 212, Folder 2606)
    - 20th Century Portraits (1943)
      - Notes for selection of portraits, n.d. (Box 212, Folder 2607-2609)
      - Memo, 1942 Aug 31 (Box 213, Folder 2610)
      - Captions for catalog and bulletin board (Box 213, Folder 2611)
      - Catalog text notes, n.d. (Box 213, Folder 2612-2613)
        Includes draft pages for a later article
      - Catalog text drafts, holograph, typescript, and carbon, corrected (Box 213, Folder 2614-2626)
      - Invitations, 1943 (Box 213, Folder 2627)
      - Transcript of interview with MW, n.d. (Box 213, Folder 2628)
      - Clippings, 1943 (Box 214, Folder 2629)
      - Scrapbook of clippings and invitations, 1941-43 (Box 214, Folder 2630)
      - "From Boldini to Picasso" article, draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 214, Folder 2631)
      - "From Boldini to Picasso" article, printed version, New York Times Magazine, 1943 Jan 3 (Box 214, Folder 2632)
      - Notecards for slide lecture, n.d. (Box 214, Folder 2633)
      - Text for slide lecture with slide list, 1943 (Box 214, Folder 2634)
    - Twenty Centuries of Mexican Art (1940)
      - Advertisement for poster competition, in Spanish, 1940 (Box 214, Folder 2635)
      - Catalog text by Montenegro, English translation, draft, typescript, corrected (Box 214, Folder 2636)
    - Wiemiler, Ignatz: Ignatz Wiemiler, Modern Binder (1935)
      - Office files, 1931-55 (Box 214, Folder 2637-2638)
    - Untitled [re: Impressionists and Expressionists] (n.d.)
      - List of works with notes, n.d. (Box 214, Folder 2639)
    - General exhibition material
      - Office file: "MOMA Exhibitions", n.d. (Box 215, Folder 2640)
      - Office file: "Exhibitions - Future", 1955-67 (Box 215, Folder 2641)
      - Office file: "MMA Exhibitions List" (Box 215, Folder 2642)
      - Invitations to various exhibitions, with notes by GW, ca. 1940s (Box 215, Folder 2643)
      - Lists of MOMA exhibitions, 1956-82 (Box 215, Folder 2644-2646)
      - Exhibition schedules and checklists, 1958-85, n.d. (Box 215, Folder 2647-2649)
  - NON-MOMA EXHIBITIONS PREPARED BY MONROE WHEELER
    - Looking South [Center for Inter-American Relations] (1972)
      - List of artists, n.d. (Box 216, Folder 2650)
      - Catalog text, drafts, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 216, Folder 2651)
      - Catalog text, galley proof, corrected, n.d. (Box 216, Folder 2652)
      - Catalog, 1972 (Box 216, Folder 2653)
    - Loren MacIver [various shows]
      - Outline for Newport Harbor Art Museum retrospective, n.d. (Box 216, Folder 2654)
      - Checklists for Newport Harbor Art Museum retrospective, n.d. (Box 216, Folder 2655)
      - Notebook, ca. 1972-81 (Box 216, Folder 2656)
        includes notes, drafts of texts, letters from LM and Robert Frash, and poem by Lloyd Frankenburg
      - Background clippings and notes, 1974, n.d. (Box 216, Folder 2657)
      - Receipt for loan to Newport Harbor Art Museum, 1983 Feb 22 (Box 216, Folder 2658)
      - Catalogs, 1970-83 (Box 216, Folder 2659)
      - Notebook of descriptive texts by LM on her paintings, 1974
    - New Jersey State Museum - "Festival '72"
      - Catalog text, drafts, holograph, typescript, and photocopy, corrected (Box 216, Folder 2660)
      - Correspondence with Intellectual Digest, 1972 (Box 216, Folder 2661)
      - Catalog text reprinted in Intellectual Digest, 1972 Nov (Box 216, Folder 2662)
    - The Textbook of the Future and its Forerunners [American Institute of Graphic Arts] (1936)
      - Catalog, 1936 Feb (Box 216, Folder 2663)
  - COMMITTEE MATERIAL
    - Architecture and design committees: acquisition lists, 1975-82 (Box 217, Folder 2664)
    - Associate Council of MOMA: annual reports, 1982-84 (Box 217, Folder 2665)
    - Budget/Finance committees: reports and office file, 1939-84, n.d. (Box 217, Folder 2666-2668)
    - Collection committees: acquisition lists, minutes, and reports, 1940-65 (Box 217, Folder 2669-2671)
    - Corporation: minutes and reports, 1946-86 (Box 217, Folder 2672-2673)
    - Drawings and prints committees: acquisition lists, agendas, members address lists, minutes, notifications and office file, 1964-87, n.d. (Box 217, Folder 2674-2679)
    - Executive committees: minutes, 1946 (Box 217, Folder 2680)
    - Exhibition committees: advance schedules, agendas, minutes, status reports, and office files, 1970-85 (Box 217, Folder 2681-2685)
    - Fine arts committees: report, 1973 (Box 217, Folder 2686)
    - Friends committees: meeting materials, [1969] (Box 217, Folder 2687)
    - Junior Council: reports and lists of members, 1972-75 (Box 218, Folder 2688-2689)
    - Painting and Sculpture committees: acquisitions lists, 1963-82 (Box 218, Folder 2690)
    - Photography committees: agendas, acquisitions lists, lists of funds, minutes, notifications, and office file, 1970-88, n.d. (Box 218, Folder 2691-2696)
    - Policy committee: office file, 1944-55 (Box 218, Folder 2697)
    - Prints and illustrated books committees: acquisitions lists, agendas, duplicate lists, minutes, notifications, purchase funds lists, and office file, 1972-88 (Box 218, Folder 2698-2704)
    - Publications committees: meeting materials, and minutes, 1967-82 (Box 219, Folder 2705-2706)
    - Steering committees: minutes, 1969 (Box 219, Folder 2707)
    - Trustees committees: agendas, lists of members, and minutes, 1963-87 (Box 219, Folder 2708-2713)
    - Trustees committees: notifications, reports, resolutions, statements, and office files, 1963-88, n.d. (Box 220, Folder 2714-2721)
    - Visual arts advisory committees: agendas, 1981 (Box 220, Folder 2722)
  - MOMA PUBLICATIONS
    - By Monroe Wheeler: Titled
      - "The Artist and the National Defense", draft, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 221, Folder 2723)
      - "Artists by Artists" appointment calendar, draft pages, holograph, typescript, and carbon, corrected, 1968 (Box 221, Folder 2724)
      - "Artists by Artists" appointment calendar, office file, 1961, 1968 (Box 221, Folder 2725)
      - Biographical sketch for René d'Harnoncourt, 1901-1968: A Tribute, background information (Box 221, Folder 2726)
      - Biographical sketch for René d'Harnoncourt, 1901-1968: A Tribute, draft pages with notes, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 221, Folder 2727)
      - Biographical sketch for Réné d'Harnoncourt, 1901-1968: A Tribute, printed version (Box 221, Folder 2728)
      - Cahiers de Georges Braque, drafts, holograph, typescript, and carbon, corrected (Box 221, Folder 2729-2730)
      - "General Administration of the Collection", mimeograph report with annotations and notes (Box 221, Folder 2731)
      - Henri Matisse: 64 Paintings, cover, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 2732)
      - Jazz by Henri Matisse, English translation, notes, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 2733)
      - Jazz by Henri Matisse, English translation, printed version, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 2734)
      - Latin American Prints, advertisement, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 2735)
      - "Lectures" office file, 1947-49 (Box 221, Folder 2736)
      - "Looking Toward the Future", draft page, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 2737)
      - "The Making of Exhibitions", office file, 1954 (Box 221, Folder 2738)
      - Membership letter: 1939, draft, typescript, corrected (Box 221, Folder 2739)
      - "A Message from Monroe Wheeler", draft, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 2740)
      - "A Museum in Wartime", draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 2741)
      - "The Nelson Aldrich Rockefeller Collection", correspondence, 1969-77 (Box 221, Folder 2742)
        includes draft of introduction by André Malraux to proposed catalog
        xref from: MOMA exhibits
      - "The Nelson Aldrich Rockefeller Collection", background information, 1958-64 (Box 221, Folder 2743-2744)
      - "The Nelson Aldrich Rockefeller Collection", notes, 1969-71 (Box 221, Folder 2745)
      - "The Nelson Aldrich Rockefeller Collection", lists of art, 1968, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 2746)
      - "The Nelson Aldrich Rockefeller Collection", schedule for catalog, [1969] (Box 221, Folder 2747)
      - "The Nelson Aldrich Rockefeller Collection", MOMA catalog, lists of color plates, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 2748)
      - "The Nelson Aldrich Rockefeller Collection", MOMA catalog, blurb drafts, typescript, photocopy, 1969 (Box 221, Folder 2749)
      - "The Nelson Aldrich Rockefeller Collection", MOMA catalog, foreword, drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1969 (Box 221, Folder 2750)
      - "The Nelson Aldrich Rockefeller Collection", MOMA catalog, preface by NAR, drafts, holograph, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1969 (Box 222, Folder 2751)
      - "The Nelson Aldrich Rockefeller Collection", MOMA catalog, lists of artworks, drafts, typescript and photocopy, corrected, 1969 Feb (Box 222, Folder 2752)
      - "The Nelson Aldrich Rockefeller Collection", MOMA catalog, essay drafts, typescript, photocopy, corrected, 1969 Mar 20 (Box 222, Folder 2753)
      - "The Nelson Aldrich Rockefeller Collection", MOMA catalog, article in MOMA Members Newsletter, 1969 (Box 222, Folder 2754)
      - "The Nelson Aldrich Rockefeller Collection", MOMA catalog, various essays, draft pages, ca. 1969 (Box 222, Folder 2755)
      - "The Nelson Aldrich Rockefeller Collection", essay [by Alfred H. Barr?], draft, typescript and photocopy, corrected (Box 222, Folder 2756)
      - "The Nelson Aldrich Rockefeller Collection", clippings, 1969 May 27 (Box 222, Folder 2757)
      - "The Nelson Aldrich Rockefeller Collection", file re: "Art considered for disposition", 1969 (Box 222, Folder 2758)
      - Rouault: "Miserere", letter from Isabelle Rouault, 1951 Jan 23 (Box 222, Folder 2759)
      - Rouault: "Miserere", notes, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 2760)
      - Rouault: "Miserere", introductory sections, draft pages, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 222, Folder 2761)
      - Rouault: "Miserere", Introduction by MW, draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 2762)
      - Rouault: "Miserere", Preface by Anthony Blunt for 1950 London edition, draft, typescript carbon, annotated (Box 222, Folder 2763)
      - Rouault: "Miserere", "The Technique of Georges Rouault's Prints" by Carl O. Schniewind, setting copy, 1946-47, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 2764)
        includes correspondence re: Rouault's case against Ambroise Vollard (1946)
      - Rouault: "Miserere", blurb, printed version, Harper's Bazaar, 1951 Dec (Box 222, Folder 2765)
      - Scroll for Alfred H. Barr, Jr., text draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 2766)
      - Statement on René d'Harnoncourt for Bienniel Report (1967-69), printed version, [1969] (Box 222, Folder 2767)
      - "Technique of Modern Art", blurb draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 2768)
      - The Writer Looks at Paintings symposium, introductory remarks, draft, typescript, with notes, 1954 (Box 222, Folder 2769)
    - By Monroe Wheeler: Untitled
      - [re: drawings], draft sections, typescript, and carbon, corrected (Box 222, Folder 2770)
      - [re: exhibition programs], drafts pages, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 2771)
      - [re: exhibition schedule], drafts pages, holograph, with notes, ca. 1941 (Box 222, Folder 2772)
      - [re: exhibitions at MOMA], draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 2773)
      - [Ghostwritten statement for donor], draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 2774)
      - [re: goals of MOMA], draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 2775)
      - [re: René d'Harnoncourt installations], correspondence, 1969 (Box 222, Folder 2776)
      - Introduction to collection of essays by artists, draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 2777)
      - [re: membership drive], draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 2778)
      - [re: MOMA and war], draft pages, typescript, corrected (Box 222, Folder 2779)
      - [re: MOMA retrospective], draft sections, holograph and typescript, corrected, ca. 1944 (Box 222, Folder 2780)
      - [Museum installations book] (with captions by MW), typescript carbon copy, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 2781)
      - [re: O'Keeffe exhibition of Stieglitz collection], notes, 1946 (Box 222, Folder 2782)
      - [re: proposed exhibitions], notes, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 2783)
      - [re: proposed exhibitions], draft pages, holograph, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 2784)
      - Responses by MW to questions on art book publishing, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 2785)
      - [re: Will Sandberg], draft pages, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1962 Oct 24 (Box 222, Folder 2786)
      - [Unidentified], acknowledgement line for catalog, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 2787)
      - Untitled loose draft pages, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 2788)
    - By Others
      - Adam, A. R.
        - "Art and Technology", typescript carbon copy (Box 223, Folder 2789)
      - Amberg, George
        - "Theatre", typescript carbon copy, n.d. (Box 223, Folder 2790)
      - Barr, Alfred H., Jr.
        - "Art in Our Time" color portfolio, foreword, typescript copy, n.d. (Box 223, Folder 2791)
        - "Art in Our Time" color portfolio, foreword, printed version, n.d. (Box 223, Folder 2792)
        - "Chronicle of the Collection of Painting and Sculpture: 1929-63", draft, typescript, photocopy, 1969 (Box 223, Folder 2793)
        - "Matisse: His Art and His Public", office files, 1929-79 (Box 223, Folder 2794)
          includes correspondence with Matisse and others
        - "The Museum Collection: A Brief Report", mimeograph copy, 1944 (Box 223, Folder 2795)
        - "Notes on the reception of the Bauhaus exhibition", mimeograph copy, n.d. (Box 223, Folder 2796)
        - "Picasso: Fifty Years of His Art", office file, 1950-64 (Box 223, Folder 2797)
        - "Preface to the Marx-Schoenborn catalogue", typescript carbon copy, n.d. (Box 223, Folder 2798)
      - Crimmins, James C.
        - Remarks upon retiring as chairman of the Junior Council, typescript copy, 1970 Jun (Box 223, Folder 2799)
      - de Kooning, Willem
        - "Address at MMA", typescript carbon copy, n.d. (Box 223, Folder 2800)
      - d'Harnoncourt, René
        - "The Art Museum's Role in International Cultural Exchange", mimeograph copy, 1963 May 23 (Box 223, Folder 2801)
        - "René's texts" office file with copies of various texts, 1964-68 (Box 223, Folder 2802)
      - Faisan, Lane, Jr.
        - "Seminars in Modern Art", proposal, n.d. (Box 223, Folder 2803)
      - Haime, Nohra
        - "The Museum of Modern Art Latin American Archive", draft, typescript, photocopy, 1978 Sep (Box 223, Folder 2804)
      - Newhall, Beaumont
        - Chapters from memoir re: MOMA, draft, typescript, corrected, photocopy, 1988 (Box 223, Folder 2805)
      - Penrose, Roland
        - "Sculpture of Picasso", office file, 1967 (Box 223, Folder 2806)
      - Read, Herbert
        - "Culture and Education in World Order", typescript carbon copy (Box 223, Folder 2807)
      - Rockefeller, Nelson
        - Remarks at MOMA reception and dinner, typescript photocopy, 1962 Oct 2 (Box 223, Folder 2808)
      - Schapiro, Meyer
        - "The Art of Pablo Picasso", typescript copy, 1939 Nov 30 (Box 223, Folder 2809)
    - Unattributed
      - Biographical sketches of MW, drafts, typescript, carbon and photocopy, 1950-66 (Box 223, Folder 2810)
      - Catalog of MOMA holdings, draft pages, typescript and photocopy, corrected (Box 223, Folder 2811)
      - Descriptions of works by French painters, draft section, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 223, Folder 2812)
      - Essay on Salvador Dali, draft sections, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 223, Folder 2813)
      - "Film India Part I. Satyajit Ray", draft page, typescript (Box 223, Folder 2814)
      - "The Life Round Table", draft page, typescript carbon (Box 223, Folder 2815)
      - "Masters of Modern Art", sample layout pages, photographs, n.d. (Box 223, Folder 2816)
      - [re: membership], draft pages, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 223, Folder 2817)
      - "Mrs. Florene May Schoenborn", draft, typescript, photocopy (Box 223, Folder 2818)
      - "Modern Art Old & New", draft page, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 223, Folder 2819)
      - "Modern Principles of Museum Administration by A. Sinnik", mimeograph copy, [ca. 1945] (Box 224, Folder 2820)
      - "The Museum of Modern Art Film Library", page proof, 1964 Dec 14 (Box 224, Folder 2821)
      - Note on Latin American writers, draft, typescript, annotated, 1941 Jan 9 (Box 224, Folder 2822)
      - Notes on Manet et ses oeuvres by A. Tabarant, draft, typescript carbon, annotated, 1967 Nov 10 (Box 224, Folder 2823)
      - Painting and Sculpture in the Museum of Modern Art, galley proof (Box 224, Folder 2824)
      - "Primitivism and Modern Art" book proposal [fragment] (Box 224, Folder 2825)
      - Program for Imrie deVegh's funeral, setting typescript, 1962 (Box 224, Folder 2826)
      - "Rene d'Harnoncourt's Installations", office file, 1969 (Box 224, Folder 2827)
      - "A Statement of Modern Art", drafts, typescript and mimeograph, corrected (Box 224, Folder 2828)
    - Other Publications material
      - Tearsheet coversheets, n.d. (Box 224, Folder 2829)
      - Memos, re: international publications program, 1956, 1960, n.d. (Box 224, Folder 2830)
      - Lists of publications, 1939-76 (Box 224, Folder 2831)
      - Statistics for costs and sales of publications (Box 224, Folder 2832)
      - Color art reproductions proofs for unidentified publications, n.d. (Box 224, Folder 2833)
    - General files re: Publications
      - "Contracts", 1968-72 (Box 224, Folder 2834)
      - "Future publications", n.d. (Box 224, Folder 2835)
      - [International Publications Program], 1952-60 (Box 224, Folder 2836)
      - "Invitations - MMA", 1949-53 (Box 224, Folder 2837)
      - "MMA Clippings", 1940-61 (Box 224, Folder 2838-2839)
        also labeled "Bill Miller's MOMA Announcements"
      - "MMA - Limited Editions", 1952 (Box 224, Folder 2840)
      - "Museum Invitations", 1949 (Box 224, Folder 2841)
      - "Museum Magazine", 1949, 1951 (Box 225, Folder 2842)
      - "New MMA Booklet", 1963-64 (Box 225, Folder 2843)
      - "Publications", 1968-71 (Box 225, Folder 2844)
      - "Publications Report", 1946-49 (Box 225, Folder 2845-2846)
      - "Work in Progress", 1954 (Box 225, Folder 2847)
  - PRINTED ITEMS
    - Acoustiguide script: "Pablo Picasso: A Retrospective", 1980 May 11 (Box 226, Folder 2848)
    - Address by Paul Tillich on the opening of the new galleries and the sculpture garden, 1964 May 25 (Box 226, Folder 2849)
    - Advance schedules, 1978 (Box 226, Folder 2850)
    - Annual reports, 1940-90 (Box 226, Folder 2851-2855)
    - Announcements and invitations, ca. 1940-87 (Box 226, Folder 2856)
    - Brochures, 1968, n.d. (Box 226, Folder 2857)
    - Bulletins, 1940-54 (Box 226, Folder 2858-2859)
    - Calendars, 1973-79 (Box 227, Folder 2860)
    - Catalogs for publications and gifts, ca. 1942-84 (Box 227, Folder 2861)
    - Circulating exhibitions catalog, 1945-46 (Box 227, Folder 2862)
    - Commercial offers and book order forms, ca. 1960-84 (Box 227, Folder 2863)
    - Dedication to MW from unidentified book, photocopy, n.d. (Box 227, Folder 2864)
    - "Easel does it or How to Canvas the Museum of Modern Art", 1975 (Box 227, Folder 2865)
    - Exhibition catalogs (not by MW), 1939-80 (Box 227, Folder 2866)
    - Exhibition information packets, 1981-86, n.d. (Box 227, Folder 2867)
    - Greeting cards and postcards, ca. 1950-80 (Box 228, Folder 2868)
    - "The History of the Motion Picture", 1946 (Box 228, Folder 2869)
    - Lee & Lee Booksellers special list of MOMA publications, n.d. (Box 228, Folder 2870)
    - Members calendars, ca. 1976-86 (Box 228, Folder 2871)
    - Members newsletters and schedule, ca. 1969-88 (Box 228, Folder 2872)
    - Membership forms, ca. 1950s-80s (Box 228, Folder 2873)
    - Memorial booklets: Iris Barry and Alfred H. Barr, Jr., 1980, 1981 (Box 228, Folder 2874)
    - "The Museum of Modern Art", by Robert Angell, offprint from Holiday Magazine, 1953 Nov (Box 228, Folder 2875)
    - MOMA Staff News, 1970-83 (Box 228, Folder 2876)
    - New acquisitions announcement, 1968 (Box 228, Folder 2877)
    - PASTA Newsletter, 1977 Dec (Box 228, Folder 2878)
    - "The Print Collection of the Museum of Modern Art" by Riva Castleman, section from unidentified printed item, n.d. (Box 228, Folder 2879)
    - Program: "Dr. Edith Sitwell in MacBeth", 1950 Nov 16 (Box 228, Folder 2880)
      Includes invitation
    - Reports, 1935-71, n.d. (Box 229, Folder 2881-2890)
  - PRESS RELEASES
    - Press releases, 1935-88, n.d. (Box 230, Folder 2891-2895)
  - CLIPPINGS
    - Mentions of, remarks by, photos of MW, ca. 1938-84 (Box 231, Folder 2896-2897)
    - MW's retirement, 1967 (Box 231, Folder 2898)
    - Books from MOMA, n.d. (Box 231, Folder 2899)
    - Exhibitions, ca. 1940-74 (Box 231, Folder 2900-2902)
    - Fire at MOMA, 1958 Apr (Box 231, Folder 2903)
    - MOMA news, ca. 1938-84 (Box 231, Folder 2904-2905)
    - Opening of Portinari exhibition, 1940 Oct 9 (Box 231, Folder 2906)
      featuring photograph of GW and Ruth Ford
    - People at MOMA, ca. 1940-87 (Box 231, Folder 2907-2909)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Artworks by Luis Covarrubias, n.d. (Box 232, Folder 2910)
    - Artworks owned by MOMA, n.d. (Box 232, Folder 2911)
    - Artworks owned by other museums, n.d. (Box 232, Folder 2912)
    - Artworks owned by MW, n.d. (Box 232, Folder 2913)
    - Artworks [principally portraits], n.d. (Box 232, Folder 2914-2915)
      possibly intended for a catalog
    - Events at MOMA, ca. 1950s (Box 232, Folder 2916)
    - Motion picture stills, contact prints: Georges Braque and George Bernard Shaw (Box 232, Folder 2917)
    - Publicity photographs for MOMA exhibits, ca. 1980s (Box 232, Folder 2918)
    - Study prints of artworks [owned by MOMA?], n.d. (Box 232, Folder 2919)
    - Study prints in file folders, arranged alphabetically by artist, n.d. (Box 232, Folder 2920-2922)
    - Tikal, Guatemala, n.d. (Box 232, Folder 2923)
  - OTHER OFFICE FILES
    - Artists' Files
      - Berard, Christian, 1949, 1951 (Box 233, Folder 2924)
      - Cartier-Bresson, Henri, 1960 (Box 233, Folder 2925)
        includes photographic prints and letter
      - Cocteau, Jean, 1962-66 (Box 233, Folder 2926)
      - Degas, Edgar, ca. 1946-50 (Box 233, Folder 2927)
      - French, Jared, n.d. (Box 233, Folder 2928)
      - MacIver, Loren, 1974-75 (Box 233, Folder 2929)
      - Matisse, Henri, 1946-77 (Box 233, Folder 2930)
      - Monet, Claude, 1948-57 (Box 233, Folder 2931)
      - Picasso, Pablo, 1973-74 (Box 233, Folder 2932)
      - Rouault, Georges, 1958-61 (Box 233, Folder 2933)
      - Shahn, Ben, 1972 (Box 233, Folder 2934)
      - Soutine, Chaim, 1954-64 (Box 233, Folder 2935)
      - Tchelitchew, Pavel, n.d. (Box 233, Folder 2936)
      - Torres-Garcia, Joaquin, 1971 (Box 233, Folder 2937)
        includes drafts of "Torres Garcia's Search for Form" by MW
      - Utrillo, Maurice, 1939-52 (Box 233, Folder 2938)
    - Reproductions of artists' works
      - Balla, Giacomo, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2939)
      - Balthus, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2940)
      - Beckmann, Max, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2941)